parts-people.com 2019-07-11

# Privacy Notice | Information Collection, Use, and Sharing | Parts-People.com

| 

### This privacy notice discloses the privacy practices for (www.parts-people.com).  This privacy notice applies solely to information collected by this Parts-People.com.  It will notify you of the following: 

###  1\. What personally identifiable information is collected from you through the website, how it is used and with whom it may be shared.   
2.  What choices are available to you regarding the use of your data.     
3.   The security procedures in place to protect the misuse of your information.    
4.   How you can correct any inaccuracies in the information. 

How we collect and use (process) your personal information

## Information Collection, Use, and Sharing

### Parts-People.com, Inc is the sole owner of the information collected on www.parts-people.com. We only have access to/collect information that you voluntarily give us via email, shopping checkout, or other direct contact from you.  We will not sell, rent, or share this information to anyone. 

**Contacting You**  
Parts-People.com  will use your information to respond to you, regarding the reason you contacted us.  We will not share your information with any third party outside of our organization, other than as necessary to fulfill your request, e.g. to ship an order.  
  
**Using This Website**  
In order to use this www.parts-people.com, as is true of most other websites, the Parts-People.com’s website collects certain information automatically and stores it in log files. The information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, the region or general location where your computer or device is accessing the internet, browser type, operating system and other usage information about the use of the Parts-People.com’s website, including a history of the pages you view. We use this information to help us design our site to better suit our users’ needs. We may also use your IP address to help diagnose problems with our server and to administer our website, analyze trends, track visitor movements, and gather broad demographic information that assists us in identifying visitor preferences. The Parts-People.com’s website also uses cookies.

**Website Registration and Purchasing**  
We request information from you on our checkout order form. To buy from us, you must provide contact information (such as first name, last name, shipping address, billing address, phone number, and email address) and financial information (like credit card number, expiration date). This information is used for billing purposes and to fill your orders. If we have trouble processing an order, we'll use this information to contact you. We may also use your email information to inform you of changes to this privacy policy.

**Credit Card Information**  
Parts-People.com does not store or save credit card information. Each time you place an order, you will be required to re-enter you credit card information.

### **Dell Service Tag**  
Parts-People.com will request Dell service tag information to help determine products compatible with your Dell PC. Parts-People.com will store this information in your website order to help Parts-People.com better offer support to you if needed in the future.   

##  **Your Access to and Control Over Information**

### You may opt out of any future contacts from us at any time.  You can do the following at any time by contacting us via the email address (info@parts-people.com) or phone number (866-816-5254) given on www.parts-people.com:

  * ###  See what data we have about you, if any. 

  * ###  Change/correct any data we have about you.

  * ###  Have us delete any data we have about you. 

  * ###  Express any concern you have about our use of your data. 

## Cookies

###  “Cookies” are small data files that may be placed on the hard drive of your computer when you visit the Parts-People.com site. Cookies permit the Parts-People's server to identify your browser whenever you interact with the Parts-People site. Parts-People uses cookies to improve the functionality of its site, to recognize repeat visits by users of its site, and to collect information about its users’ interactions with the Services. These Cookies contain identification information that enables us to streamline your experiences using the Services and the Parts-People site. These cookies may be placed by Parts-People or by select third party partners we collaborate with. To learn more or to opt out of placement of these cookies, visit the[ Network Advertising Initiative](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/) website or [Digital Advertising Alliance](http://www.aboutads.info/) website. You are always free to set your browser software to decline cookies. However, if you decline cookies, you will be required to reenter your login information each time you access the Services, and you may not be able to optimize the features of the Services. In some cases, you will not be able to access Services if cookies are disabled. By agreeing to accept cookies from Parts-People.com’s site, the following types of cookies could be placed on your computer. 

  * **Social Media Cookies:** These cookies are used to integrate our site with popular social media sites (Facebook, Twitter, etc.). Social Media cookies allow visitors to share content quickly and easily with their social networks

  * **Analytics Cookies:** These cookies are used to measure website traffic and activity

  * **Advertising Cookies:** These cookies help correlate online advertising to a visitor’s interests by displaying marketing messages that are relevant to a user based on a user’s browsing history and preferences. 

## **Security**

### We take precautions to protect your information.  When you submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and offline using 256bit TLS1.2 encryption. 

Wherever we collect sensitive information (such as credit card data), that information is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way.  You can verify this by looking for a closed lock icon at the bottom of your web browser, or looking for "https" at the beginning of the address of the web page. Credit Cards numbers entered on www.parts-people.com are not stored or saved. 

While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to perform a specific job (for example, billing or customer service) are granted access to personally identifiable information.  The computers/servers in which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment. 

## **Contact Us**

### If you feel that we are not abiding by this privacy policy, you should contact us immediately via telephone at 512-339-1990 or via email info@parts-people.com.  
  
---
